Guide to the Cedric Belfrage Papers TAM.143
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Series IV: Writings, 1927-1990
  - Subseries IV:A: Travel Notes, 1956-1977
    - Travel Notes from Spain., 1971 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Travel Notes from Cuba and correspondence., 1975-1977 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Subseries IV:B: Articles, 1946-1987
    - Journalism correspondence., 1946-1955 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Published articles., ca.1948-1960 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - The Strange Case of the 16 Tokyo Roses (Unpublished Article)., 1956 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Foreign Language Articles., 1956-1959 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Journalism notes., ca.1957-1959 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Typescripts of articles by C.B., 1966 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Book reviews and articles for the Progressive and In These Times., 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Book Reviews by C.B., ca.1969-1979 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - How I Broke the Atlantic Round Trip Record., 1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Guardian Articles and book reviews., 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Subseries IV:C: Translations, 1966-1989
    - Eduardo Galeano correspondence., 1972-1988 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Translation reviews., ca.1976 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Translation correspondence and manuscripts: Galeano and others., 1966-1984 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Translation correspondence and manuscripts: Galeano and others., 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Memory of Fire: Translation correspondence., 1984-1989 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Subseries IV:D: Published Writings, 1937-1990
    - Let My People Go: Review., 1940 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence from readers of C.B.'s books., 1937-1956 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Book contracts., 1939-1971 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Upside Down On Horse Back: Novel manuscript, preliminary draft of "Abide With Me.", 1940 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Deadline - Democracy: Outline of book in preparation by C.B. and Jim Aronson, Preliminary Draft of Seeds of Destruction., ca.1947 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Reviews of "Abide With Me.", ca.1948-1951 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - The Frightened Giant: Scotty Mackenzie / The Admiral correspondence., 1955-1965 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - The Admiral / The Frightened Giant manuscript., 1957 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - The Admiral / The Frightened Giant manuscript., 1957 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - The Admiral / The Frightened Giant manuscript., 1957 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - 'The Frightened Giant' proposal, reviews and correspondence., 1955-1957 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - 'My Master Columbus' correspondence and contract., 1960 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - 'My Master Columbus' reviews., 1961 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - 'The Man At The Door With the Gun' reviews., 1964 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - 'seeds of Destruction' correspondence in German., 1966-1967 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Book Procurements from publishers., 1971-1982 (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - 'Away From It All' review., 1974 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - 'something to Guard' grant application., 1974 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - 'something to Guard' notes., ca.1977-1978 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - 'something to Guard'; "A Personal Note" (To Readers)., 1978 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Cedric Belfrage Biographical Data (Joke autobiographical sketch for book cover by C.B.)., ca.1978 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - 'something to Guard' Royalty statements and book orders., 1979 (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - 'something to Guard' correspondence., 1975-1980 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Reviews of 'something to Guard:' Articles and correspondence., 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Royalty statements for books by C.B., 1979-1985 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Editorial correspondence: With publishers regarding publication of books; with literary agents regarding ideas for books and attempts to get books published; with readers and friends responding to books; bills and invoices., 1937-1949 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Editorial correspondence., 1950-1958 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Editorial correspondence., 1960-1969 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Editorial correspondence., 1970-1979 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Editorial correspondence., 1980-1990 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Subseries IV:E: Unpublished Writings, 1941-1980
    - 'stab In The Dark' Novel notes and character descriptions., 1941 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - 'The King is Naked: A Primer of Heresy for my First Born' Manuscript., 1946 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Notes and manuscript on Nazi Germany newspaper., ca.1947 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Fritz - Meet The Free Press Manuscript about Shaef press control., ca.1947 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Memo on Time-Life-Luce book project., 1949 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Raymond Robbins Biography project manuscripts, notes and correspondence., 1949-1956 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - 'The Testament of a Heretic' Tentative outline for a book., 1950 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - 'Beggars In Velvet: A Book About Charity' Book outline., ca.1951 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - 'Beggars In Velvet' Book project notes and correspondence., ca.1951 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Unfinished Fiction Projects., ca.1952 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - 'My Au Revoir to America' manuscript., ca.1956 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Topolobampo Book project correspondence, source material and notes., ca.1959-1964 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Bartolome De Las Casas Book project., ca.1969-1971 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - 'Who Were The Rosenbergs? The Nine Lives of A Heretic' manuscript, draft for an autobiography., 1974 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Emiliano Zapata Biography manuscript., ca.1975 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - The View from Cuernavaca speech at First Unitarian Church of Los Angeles., ca.1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Untitled novel outline., undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Nudery novel character descriptions and notes., undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Problems of Corpse Disposal In US manuscript., undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - An Encyclopedia of Useless Information synopsis., undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - The American Standard of Dying; play manuscript., undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Man Bites Dog In Mexico manuscript., undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - How to Stop Thinking notes., undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - The Person Game Unfinished manuscript., undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Latin America., undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Miscellaneous unpublished writings and notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Subseries IV:F: Published Writings: American Inquisition, 1945-1989
    - An Account of American Heresies and The Manner of Their Suppression (Rough draft of introduction)., ca.1970 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Bibliographical Information., ca.1973 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Book Orders., 1976-1979 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Comments on Manuscript., 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence regarding attempts to find publisher., 1967-1970 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence regarding attempts to find publisher., 1971-1973 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence regarding grant., 1967-1969 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley: Responses to questionnaire on her expulsion from the ACLU in 1940, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - High Wind In Miami Chapter 23 manuscript., ca.1970 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Literary biographical sketches of C.B., ca.1973 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Manuscript changes., ca.1970 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Mitford, Jessica, her foreword for republication of 'American Inquisition.', ca.1989 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 1., ca.1945-1960 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 2., ca.1945-1950 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 3., ca.1945-1950 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 4., ca.1945-1950 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 5., ca.1945-1950 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 6., ca.1950 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 7., ca.1951-1953 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 8., ca.1950-1955 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 9., ca.1954 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 10., ca.1959 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 11., ca.1960-1966 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 12., ca.1966-1968 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Chronology of Events., 1952-1955 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Outline, character descriptions, subject index., ca.1968 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Proposal., 1967 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Publicity., ca.1973-1976 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Reflections on Becoming a Lampshade, "How My Thoughts Became Dangerous" (Rough Draft of Beginning)., ca.1970 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Republication of 'American Inquisition.', 1989 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - Republication of 'American Inquisition' correspondence., 1984-1985 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Subseries IV:G: Published Writings: American Inquisition - Research, 1945-1978
    - Marion Bachrach., ca.1955-1957 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Nicholas Bela., ca.1953 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Elizabeth Bentley., ca.1949-1946 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Louise Berman., ca.1949 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Dr. Albert Blumberg., ca.1954-1956 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Kay Boyle and Joseph Franckenstein., ca.1952-1957 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Louis Budenz., ca.1950-1957 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Matt Cvetic., ca.1950-1954 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Bella Dodd., ca.1952-1961 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Virginia Durr's Statement At New Orleans Hearings on Southern Conference For Human Welfare., 1954 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Albert Einstein and Thomas Mann Speeches and letters on HUAC and the Cold War, undated (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Simon Gerson and Isidore Begun acquittal., ca.1952 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Gil Green., ca.1956-1957 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Ralph H. Gundlach., 1949-1952 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Claudia Jones., ca.1955 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Steve Nelson., ca.1957-1956 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Linus Pauling., ca.1950-1963 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Herbert A. Philbrick Case., ca.1957-1959 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Irving Potash., ca.1954-1955 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Ethel and Julius Rosenberg and Morton Sobell., ca.1952-1963 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Junius Scales., ca.1954-1958 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Leo Sheiner., ca.1956 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Agnes Smedley., 1949 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Robert Thompson., ca.1953-1957 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Fred Williams., 1959 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Biographies of people called before congressional committees for alleged Communist Party affiliation., ca.1970 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born., ca.1955-1960 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - CIA., ca.1965-1967 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Cleveland Taft-Hartley conspiracy case., 1958 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - 'Counter-Attack Red Channels'., ca.1950 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - House Unamerican Activities Committee chronology., ca.1945-1955 (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Informers., ca.1970 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Lost Books correspondence., 1970 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Perjury Cases., ca.1954-1958 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Philadelphia communist trials:, ca.1953-1955 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous individuals and organizations., undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Miscellaneous source material and notes., ca.1969-1971 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence., ca.1965-1969 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Reviews (articles and correspondence)., 1971-1976 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - 'The Spanish Inquisition' Chapter 1 manuscript., ca.1968 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Waldorf-Astoria Cultural-Scientific Peace Conference: responses to questionnaire., 1968 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Waldorf-Astoria Cultural-Scientific Peace Conference: Responses organized by answer to questionnaire., 1968 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Campaign for Visa to visit the U.S. correspondence with congressmen., 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Campaign for visa to visit U.S.: general correspondence., 1972-1973 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - C.B.'s return to the U.S.: correspondence and invitations., 1972-1974 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Campaign for visa to visit U.S.: Interview at U.S. Embassy and editorial by C.B. about trip., 1973 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - C.B.'s return to U.S. articles., 1973-1975 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - C.B.'s return to U.S. speeches., 1973 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - C.B.'s return to U.S. itinerary, notebook and announcements of lectures., 1973 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Biographical Information., ca.1976 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence. December, 1973-1977 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence. April, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Research material and notes., 1971-1978 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Subseries IV:H: American Inquisition - Leo Sheiner and Miami Red Cases, 1946-1961
    - Edwin Waller Research file for Leo Sheiner Case., 1948, 1956 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Summons., 1954 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Transcript of record of Florida Supreme Court., 1954 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Opinion and judgement., 1954 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Paul Crouch research file., 1954-1955 (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Joseph Mazzei research file., 1954-1956 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Articles., 1955-1956 (Box 21, Folder 15)
    - Transcript of testimony., 1956 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Witnesses., 1956 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Recusation and judgement., 1956 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Index to transcript of Record of Florida Supreme Court., 1956 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Preparation of appendix in State-vs-Sheiner., 1957 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Copy of proceedings from appeal to Supreme Court., 1957 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence with Lawyers., 1956-1958 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Reversal of disbarment., 1956-1959 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Articles., 1947-1955 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Transcript of record of proceedings of Florida-vs-Jimmy Sullivan., 1948 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Jacob Burck briefs., 1953-1954 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Thomas Kelly hearings., 1954 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Southern Conference Educational Fund (SCEF) Hearings., 1954 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Summary and background of the violent outbreak of McCarthyism in Miami., 1954 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Joseph Weinberg hearing., 1954 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Crouch and Sheiner's Testimony before hearings subcommittee to investigate administration of Internal Security Act., 1954 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - HUAC hearings., 1954 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - How legislative inquisitions stifle integration and social progress SCEF pamphlet., 1961 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - McCarthy Era scrap book of newspaper clippings., 1946-1960 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Subseries IV:I: Memoirs, 1974-1981
    - Memoirs, undated (Box not specified, Folder data_value_missing_7cedc1a4a39fac84226d3a5a0cbb0468)
    - Autobiography Outline., ca.1974 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Antisemitism Introduction., ca.1981 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Olga, manuscript, notes and correspondence., ca.1981 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Eileen, manuscript, notes, correspondence & source material., ca.1981 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Emil Carlebach, 'De-Nazification of German Press,' manuscript, notes, correspondence and source material., ca.1981 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Frank Scully, manuscript, notes and correspondence., ca.1981 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Frank Scully, manuscript, notes, correspondence and source material., ca.1981 (Box 22, Folder 14)
  - Subseries IV:J: Unpublished Writings - Hollywood Book, 1927-1984
    - Biographical Articles., 1931-1932 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Sunday Express articles., 1931 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Sunday Express articles., 1932 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Sunday Express articles., 1932 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Sunday Express articles., 1933-1934 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - S Sunday Express articles from trip around the world., 1934 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Daily Express articles., 1935 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - BBC film criticism., 1927-1932 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Thames Television interview about Hollywood., ca.1973 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Film Weekly articles., 1928-1930 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Manuscript - outline, introduction & chapters 1-7., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Manuscript - introduction, chapters 1-7, & synopsis of remaining chapters., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Manuscript (unfinished) - chapters 2-3., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Feedback and Hollywood articles., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Manuscript, index and letter from Kevin Brownlow., 1984 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Notes & source material on Tom Mix & Hobart Bosworth., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Draft of Introduction., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence., 1985-1986 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - General., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Dupes and Dopes., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Sex and Censors., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Custard Pies., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Road to Mecca (Getting There Chapter)., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Louella Parsons, ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Cecil B. De Mille: notes and source material., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Clara Bow, ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Greta Garbo, ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Hucksters, ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - By Royal Appointment, ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - H.K. Thaw, ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Talkies, ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Hand-Biters, ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Articles by C.B., 1924-1929 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Articles by C.B., 1930-1932, undated (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - correspondence., 1927-1984 (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - General., ca.1984 (Box 24, Folder 26)
  - Subseries IV:K: Unpublished Writings - Owen Whitfield Book, 1947-1985
    - Notes on visit to Owen Whitfield., 1947 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Cotton Patch Moses: article about Owen Whitfield by C.B., 1948 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Hugh Goodrum Novel: outline and first two chapters., ca.1948 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Hugh Goodrum Novel: chapter notes., ca.1948 (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Thad Snow research file., 1942-1955 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - From Missouri - Xerox of book by Thad Snow (research for Owen Whitfield book)., 1954 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Thad and Whit correspondence., 1982-1984 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Thad and Whit source materials, research notes, indexed book notes and chronologies., ca.1982 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Thad and Whit fiction version., 1982 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Thad and Whit foreword and book outline., 1982 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 1., 1982 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 2., 1982 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 3., 1982 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 3a., 1982 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 4 & 5., 1982 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 6., 1982 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 7., 1982 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 6., 1985 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 7., ca.1985 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 8., ca.1985 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Chapters 9, 10 and 11., ca.1985 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Owen Whitfield: fiction version manuscript and notes., ca.1985 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Two American Devils: proposal, outline and literary biographical sketch of C.B., 1985 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Subseries IV:L: ADDENDUM to Published Writings: American Inquisition and My Master Columbus, 1959-1990
    - American Inquisition: Bibliography, Drafts, Index, Fragments of Manuscript, 1971-1973; 1990 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - American Inquisition: Correspondence, Comments, Corrections, 1969 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - American Inquisition: Draft (ch. 1-14), ca.1969 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - American Inquisition: Draft (ch. 15-End), ca.1969 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - American Inquisition: Draft (ch. 1-14), ca.1972 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - American Inquisition: Draft (ch. 15-End), ca.1972 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - My Master Columbus: Draft (ch. 1-10), ca.1960 (Box 26, Folder 20)
    - My Master Columbus: Draft (ch. 11-22), ca.1960 (Box 26, Folder 21)
    - My Master Columbus: Draft (23-37), ca.1960 (Box 26, Folder 22)
    - My Master Columbus: Notes, ca.1960 (Box 26, Folder 23)
    - My Master Columbus: Notes, Correspondence, etc., ca.1959-1960 (Box 26, Folder 24)
    - Mein Herr Kolumbus (Book Jacket), Undated (Box 26, Folder 25)
- Series V: Addendum, 1923-2003
  The Addendum contains correspondence of Cedric Belfrage, of his widow Mary Belfrage, a typescript of and unpublished autobiography by Cedrice, "Nine Lives of a Heretic," other writings by CB, including a typescript "The Jews and I," FOIA files obtained by Belfrage biographer Jennifer Palmer, correspondence and other materials relating to the Cuernavaca Belfrage home insofar as it served as a guest house for various leftists traveling abroad, and biographical information on Mary Belfrage.
  - Belfrage, Cedric: Biography, "The 9 Lives of A Heretic", undated (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Belfrage, Cedric: condolences, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 1a)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; correspondence, 1945; 1973 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Deportation press statement, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Espionage charges clippings, 1996 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Cedric Belfrage from the World Wide Web, undated (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; letters to Mary Belfrage, 1959-1960 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; letters to Mary Belfrage (photocopies), 1960 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Memorial guest book, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Memorial, quotes for, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Passports and other travel documents, 1950s-1990s (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; "America Standard of Dying," Black and White, October, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings, "Amy", undated (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Away from it All," volume 2 typscript, undated (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "The Case of the Stubborn Editor, 1955 (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; "Forest Lawn Beckons You," Black and White, Novemeber, 1939 (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; "The Jews and I" (unpublished transcript), undated (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: memoir (file version), 1982 (Box 27, Folder 17)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," table of contents (unpublished autobiography), undated (Box 27, Folder 18)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," draft, undated (Box 27, Folder 19)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," incomplete draft, pp. 1-84 (photocopy), undated (Box 27, Folder 20)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," incomplete draft, miscellaneous portions (photocopy), undated (Box 27, Folder 21)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic": Misc. 6 pp., Undated (Box 27, Folder 22)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," "1938" (copy), undated (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: " Nine Lives of a Heretic," prelude, undated (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic,' Chapter 2, undated (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," Chapter 3, undated (Box 27, Folder 26)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," chapter 4, undated (Box 27, Folder 27)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," Chapter 5, undated (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," Chapter 5, Inquisitor, 1. A History Lesson, undated (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," Chapter 6 (re DuBois), undated (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writing: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," Chapter 7, Inquisitor, pp. 108-157, undated (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," Chapter 8, "Jailbird", undated (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Nine Lives of a Heretic," Chapter 8, "Editor is Bonkers", undated (Box 27, Folder 33)
  - Belfrage, Cedric; Writings: "Politics Catches up with the Writer," New Masses, December 28, 1937 (Box 27, Folder 34)
  - Belfrage, Cedric and Mary; Personal documents: marriage, ect., 1923-1990 (Box 27, Folder 35)